Hello, all my friends, and welcome again to the complete data structure and algorithms and scores
in this video, we are going to exercise seven is six and we start solving it.
So this exercise is telling us to sort a stack using recursion.
We need to create a method that sorts a stack using recursion.
OK.
Post the video and think about that, how we can sort it stack.
Using their cash, we need to pop all the elements and start.
Searching for the minimum between among these elements, and we start inserting and pushing them into
the stack and gain by increasing order.
This is our algorithm how we are going to sort this stack.
But we are going to use that recursion.
OK.
So I will create a method here called list of Typekit static void called sort the stack.
It's very important.
And it took into perimeter a stack.
Valuable of Typekit.
We didn't specify any genetics because we are not going to make it complex now till now, later on in
the next exercise, we are going to implement a genetics and we can make it as stack of integers here.
OK, but then now we are going to implement a stack and we are dealing with a stack of integers.
OK.
So let's start checking if the stack is not empty and if it is empty, if there's empty, we are not
going to insert anything.
If it is not our sort, anything, if there's not empty, if it's is not empty.
OK, we are going to start with these steps.
First of all, remove the top item.
OK.
By making Intex equal to as thought part.
Method and the second step is sorting
the remaining
stack by executing their short stack method again using recursion.
OK.
You see, guys, here is the recursion.
See this last by using their recursion.
Now we are going to make a new method that will insert the sorted items into the stack, so we have
pulled the items from the stack popping.
The top of the top item from the stack, and we are going till we have reached that as is empty, if
as is empty, we are not we are not going to execute anything and we will get rolled back by executing
the remaining concept.
But the remaining concept is not sorting the stack.
We need to push the top item back into this sorted.
Stack, so push their top item back in sorted stack.
Guys, it's very important we start popping.
The items we execute this until reaching the end of the stack and after reaching the end of the stack
will start rolling back and pushing them in and insert them into their stack using the sort that insert.
So I will make a method called sorted insert that they'll care about they're inserting, but this time
by inserting them into increasing order into a sorted manner.
OK.
So I work past Stack and X, OK?
It took into 30 meters of the stack and it took into the perimeter that they're removed.
Right?
OK.
So let's go and insert.
And so create the method sorted in the insert I will create as plus enter create the method here.
So.
It took into the burden meter stack, and it took into the meter and index that we are going to make
the and insert it again.
So the base case, either the stack is empty or new, newly inserted item is greater than the top.
More than an existing, we start by checking if SE is empty.
OK, remember, guys, we are going to insert the elements back, but here and this time we are going
to insert them in a sorted manner.
We have seen this in the reverse, the same concept of the reverse.
But in this way, we are going to insert them in a sorted man.
If a stack is empty or x greater, then ask Dot B is greater than the first element, then don't do
anything.
OK.
If it stack is empty, sorry or s great, the X greater than the stack that peak.
If this met, these conditions are not the true don't make anything.
But if they are true, either we are creating a new and we are inserting data inside a new stack or
empty stack, or we are inserting item that that is greater than that thought, which is good because
consider if we have at the top
seven and we are going to insert eight.
Yes, it took because it's very it's very obvious that eight is greater than seven and it will apply
and obeys the rule of increasing order.
But we if we are trying to insert the three, if three stack that peak, if X, which is three greater
than seven, no, it's less then.
So we are not going to the certainty.
OK.
It's very important.
Stack OK, so stack dot, push x and serve it and return.
This return is very important because we are dealing with recursion and recursion.
This is the base concept.
This is called the base case and always used the base case and recursion in order to indicate the end
of recursion and prevent entering into an infinite, looping and infinite recursion.
Now, if the work is great or.
Remove that off the top right and clamp equal as that followed and sort that sort that stack.
Certain inserts or that insert, and I will try to sort it and pass acts.
The third thing that I need to make that stack the push their stamp.
OK.
This is how we make a sword that is stark and sadistic.
Now let's add
items here and try to sort them.
Can't be.
Saw the stack.
So we called Stack the.
Saw.
They are sort.
Sort of stacked the press deck and stacked it.
Brent.
Thank.
That's Ron Nancy.
Here we go.
We have four, four, 44, 86, 74 and nine.
OK.
After pumping, we have removed our name.
We have 74.
We are reversing it 74, 86, 44, and.
The stack.
We are sorting the stack 44, 74 and 86.
So we have this stack four, four, eight, six and seven four.
We have sorted this stack and we get the four, four, seven four and eight six.
OK.
This is the algorithm behind sorting their stack using reCAPTCHA.